<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>ClearlyElevated</title>
    <link href="https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://nolan-tanzman.github.io" />
    <updated>1969-12-31T16:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Nolan Tanzman</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nolan-tanzman.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Vancouver Man Arrested / Child Sexual Assult</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nolan Tanzman</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/vancouver-man-arrested-child-sexual-assult/"/>
        <id>https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/vancouver-man-arrested-child-sexual-assult/</id>
            <category term="Washington State"/>
            <category term="Law Enforcement"/>

        <updated>2020-09-30T09:42:21-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Vancouver, Wash. – On July 1, 2020, the Kalama, Washington Police Department&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<p class="msg msg--info" dir="auto"><em><strong>Vancouver, Wash. – On July 1, 2020,</strong></em> the<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong> Kalama, Washington Police Department</strong> </em></span>began a <em>child sexual exploitation investigation involving a 14 year old victim who was being groomed for sex by a 39 year old male in Florida.</em></p>
<div dir="auto"><hr></div>
<div dir="auto">The male had been communicating with the girl for several months over a variety of social media platforms and was posing online as a 20 year old. As the primary Department of Justice Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force (ICAC) affiliate in SW Washington, the Vancouver Police Department’s Digital Evidence Cybercrime Unit (DECU) was requested to provide assistance in the case. DECU detectives and Kalama Police met with the victim and her family, then assumed her online persona and began an undercover operation to identify and expose the suspect.</div>
<div dir="auto"><hr></div>
<div dir="auto">During online chats with the man, detectives learned the he was currently somewhere in Vancouver, Washington and was making plans to meet the victim. Because the suspect knew the location of the victim’s residence, the victim and her family were notified and a safety plan was set up with Kalama Police Department. DECU detectives immediately wrote warrants and emergency orders to several electronic and online service providers in an attempt to locate the suspect.</div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<p class="msg msg--highlight  msg--info msg--success" dir="auto">After finding the suspect in the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>downtown area of Vancouver</strong></span>, detectives from the <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Vancouver Police Department Neighborhood Response Teams</span></strong> set up surveillance, while DECU detectives continued chatting with him. The suspect advised he was on his way to the victim’s house to bring her a cell phone and was observed leaving his hotel on a bicycle. <em><strong>He arrived shortly thereafter at the victim’s house where he was seen by detectives hiding a plastic bag in the victim’s backyard.</strong> </em>He was arrested without incident by surveillance teams. The bag was later found to contain a cell phone hidden in a box of gum packets, some chocolate bars and a love letter to the victim.</p>
<div dir="auto"><hr></div>
A subsequent <span style="text-decoration: underline;">search warrant</span> on the<code> three phones</code> the<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> suspect possessed revealed the sexually exploitive chats with the victim and DECU undercover officers, thousands of depictions of minors engaged in sexually explicit activity and a Google map used to located the victim’s residence. </span>The love letter found in the bag detailed the man’s obsession for the girl and how he had immediately gone to her house after arriving in Washington on a bus. He also explained that he purchased her the cell phone so they could communicate secretly. The letter went further to detail that he even watched the victim’s younger brother playing in the yard</strong>.</div>
<div><hr></div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q"><strong>Detectives executed a search warrant at the suspect’s hotel room and located what appears to be a kidnappers kit which included</strong><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> heavy duty flex cuffs, handcuffs, duct tape, rubber gloves, face wrap/blindfold, lubricant, a sex toy, several large knives, a hatchet, and a .45 caliber handgun and ammunition. An additional cell phone, laptop computer and a thumb drive</span></em> were also seized and are being forensically examined. <code><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>Samuel Aaron Leonard, 04/18/81, of New Port Richey, Florida</strong></em></span></code>, was arrested and booked on the <span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;"><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #ff0000;"><strong>f<span style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">ollowing charges:</span></strong></span></span>
<div dir="auto"><hr></div>
</div>
<p dir="auto"><span style="color: #ff0000;"><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><code>[#1] Communication with a minor for immoral purposes</code></strong></span></em></span></p>
<p dir="auto"><span style="color: #ff0000;"><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><code><span style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">[#2] Possession of child pornography in the 1st degree</span></code></strong></span></em></span></p>
<p dir="auto"><span style="color: #ff0000;"><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><code><span style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">[#3] Dealing of child pornography in the 1st degree</span></code></strong></span></em></span></p>
<p dir="auto"><span style="color: #ff0000;"><em><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><code><span style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">[#4] Sexual exploitation of a minor</span></code></strong></span></em></span></p>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto"><hr></div>
<div dir="auto">Significant follow up will be conducted by DECU in the coming weeks, including computer forensics on numerous cell phones, the laptop and the thumb drive that all appear to have depictions from hundreds of other minors the suspect was communicating with across the United States. DECU is currently working with Florida ICAC teams in the Pasco, County Florida area to serve warrants on the suspect’s residence.</div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto"><em>The Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) special agent</em> assigned to <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>DECU</strong> </em>will be referring this case to the U.S. Attorney’s Office Western District for consideration of federal charges related to his travel across state lines to facilitate these crimes.</span></div>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">This case could easily have had a tragic ending had alert parents and siblings of the victim not been paying close attention and alerted authorities. The Vancouver and Kalama Police departments are very grateful for the cooperation and assistance given by this family and the numerous law enforcement agencies involved in this case.</div>
<div dir="auto"><hr></div>
</div>
<p class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q msg msg--highlight "><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><strong>The Vancouver Police Department and the Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force encourages anyone who believes a child is being exploited online to call 9-1-1 to report their concerns to law enforcement immediately.</strong></em></span></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>North county residents heed pre-evacuation notices as Gifford Pinchot burns</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nolan Tanzman</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/north-county-residents-heed-pre-evacuation-notices-as-gifford-pinchot-burnstrending/"/>
        <id>https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/north-county-residents-heed-pre-evacuation-notices-as-gifford-pinchot-burnstrending/</id>
            <category term="Weather"/>
            <category term="Washington State"/>

        <updated>2020-09-30T09:42:21-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    <section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7">
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">After receiving a “Get Ready” evacuation notice, Amboy resident Judie Woodruff stayed awake until 1 a.m. Thursday packing essential belongings — important documents and other irreplaceable possessions — and loading them into a trailer.</span></p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7">
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">After receiving a “Get Ready” evacuation notice, Amboy resident Judie Woodruff stayed awake until 1 a.m. Thursday packing essential belongings — important documents and other irreplaceable possessions — and loading them into a trailer.</span></p>

<p class="p1"><em><span class="s1">She wasn’t the only one preparing for the worst.</span></em></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Residents in north Clark County remained on alert Thursday, awaiting news on any updates to evacuation notices issued Wednesday night, due to the Big Hollow wildfire burning east near Yale Reservoir in the Gifford Pinchot National Forest.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">As of Thursday morning, the last available update before press time, the fire had not entered Clark County, and there were no mandatory evacuations in place, according to Clark Regional Emergency Services Agency.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s1">But people in Yacolt and Amboy described the conditions as “very smoky,” with orange-tinted skies, a blood-red sun and ash falling in some areas.</span></code></p>
</div>
</section>
<div class="article-inline advertisement my-6">
<div class="container-fluid text-center my-6">
<div id="instory-full-width-1"> </div>
</div>
</div>
<section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7">
<p class="p1"><span class="s1"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Woodruff</strong> </span>said:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">there’s a dirty film on vehicles, and she can taste the smoke in the air.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p class="p1"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span class="s1"><strong>Estimates of the size of the fire have varied greatly since Wednesday night, and it continues to grow. However, both the:</strong></span></span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">U.S. Forest Service and Washington Department of Natural Resources estimated the fire has burned about 12,000 acres.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Video shot Thursday morning by KPTV-TV from a helicopter showed the fire burning on a ridge in the forest. Flames were seen crowning in the tops of trees in the heavily timbered area, and producing a large plume of smoke.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Carrie Bladow, a member of Yacolt Community Church, said she is </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">keeping a watchful eye on fire maps in case the blaze creeps too close to town for comfort.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The church is doing its best to inform members of the evolving situation. People are preparing for the worst, but Bladow said she is making an effort to not instill needless fear.</span></p>
</div>
</section>
<section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7">
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">“We’ve had some of our elderly folks call who are concerned. No one’s home is threatened at this point, but we’re telling everyone to be ready, in addition to just checking up on them, asking if they’re OK,” Bladow said. “There were some rumors going around (Wednesday) night about how close (the fire) was, so I’ve been directing people to the map. That’s the most concrete information.”</span></p>

<h3 class="p2"><code><strong>Evacuation notices</strong></code></h3>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">The Department of Natural Resources on Wednesday issued a Level 1 “Get Ready” evacuation notice for the north Yacolt and Amboy areas and a Level 2 “Get Set” notice for Chelatchie Prairie.</span></code></p>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">CRESA issued a public alert about the evacuation notices Wednesday night. The agency said there is no immediate threat to those areas. However, fire officials want residents to be aware of the situation in case conditions change. A map of the affected areas can be found at <a href="https://bit.ly/35nOnME">https://bit.ly/35nOnME</a>.</span></code></p>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">Battle Ground Public Schools has closed Yacolt Primary School and Amboy Middle School and canceled remote learning because of the evacuation notices. There is no meal service at those sites. The Woodland School District closed Yale Elementary School due to the Level 2 evacuation notice in that area and heavy smoke.</span></code></p>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">A Level 1 evacuation notice means residents should be aware of the potential danger and should “get ready” in the event of a mandatory evacuation.</span></code></p>
</div>
</section>
<div class="article-inline advertisement my-6">
<div class="container-fluid text-center my-6">
<div id="instory-full-width-3"> </div>
</div>
</div>
<section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7">
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">“Residents with special needs, or those with pets or livestock, should take note and prepare for relocating family members, pets and livestock. Refine your evacuation plans and gather the things you will need if you must evacuate,” CRESA explained in social media posts.</span></code></p>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">A Level 2 evacuation notice indicates a significant risk in the area.</span></code></p>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">“Now is the time to be set for immediate evacuation. Residents should either voluntarily relocate to a shelter or designated area or with family/friends outside the area or be ready to leave at a moment’s notice,” according to the agency.</span></code></p>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">A Level 3 “Go Now” notice means there’s immediate danger and residents need to evacuate.</span></code></p>
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s2">CRESA has designated Lewisville Intermediate Campus, 406 N.W. Fifth Ave., Battle Ground, as the meeting point for anyone who needs to evacuate.</span></code></p>
</div>
</section>
<div class="article-inline advertisement my-6">
<div class="container-fluid text-center my-6">
<div id="instory-full-width-4"> </div>
</div>
</div>
<section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7"><hr>
<h3 class="p2"><strong>Helping hands</strong></h3>
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">Woodruff said some north county residents have begun moving animals from their properties. People are stepping up, offering help to move them to safer areas using trailers, she said.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">“Everyone is helping each other out, and most everyone is getting important stuff together,” Woodruff said.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1 msg msg--info"><span class="s2">Clark County Executive Horse Council’s Adopt-a-Horse program posted a request on Facebook asking people with space in their barns or on their properties to consider housing horses evacuated due to the fire.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">The council is working with the county’s dispatchers and animal control officers to coordinate those efforts. It’s also looking for anyone willing to take in livestock, such as goats and sheep. Anyone willing to help should call Lori Harris at 360-798-3515.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">Harris said the number of calls over the past couple of days has been overwhelming, but she and others are teaming up to help people move animals here and from Oregon.</span></p>
</blockquote>
</div>
</section>
<div class="article-inline advertisement my-6">
<div class="container-fluid text-center my-6">
<div id="instory-full-width-5"> </div>
</div>
</div>
<section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7">
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">Large barns in the county, such as Rockin’ B Ranch in Ridgefield, and organizations, such as Clark County Saddle Club, have offered space and taken in donated hay and feed for the animals. The Clark County Event Center at the Fairgrounds is also being used, with many of the animals there coming from Oregon.</span></p>
<p class="p1 msg msg--highlight "><span class="s2">There were more than 250 displaced animals being sheltered in the county as of Thursday, and Harris said she expects that total to climb.</span></p>
<hr>
<p class="p1"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span class="s2"><strong>Robert Lies, a day manager at Yacolt Trading Post, said</strong> </span></span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">customers seem a bit panicked about the current situation, because the area has not experienced a fire of this magnitude in recent memory.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">He said some older residents are comparing it with the Yacolt Burn, fires that scorched the area starting more than a century ago and the reburns that persisted until 1952.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">“I get the feeling that some people are nervous. I’m doing my best to smooth over those feelings,” Lies said.</span></p>
</blockquote>
</div>
</section>
<section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7">
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">A number of residents stayed in nearby hotels overnight, he said.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s2">Lies said the store is doing its best to keep people supplied. Several customers have rented storage sheds for their belongings, and many others seem to be grabbing ice. Beyond that, customers are sticking to their ordinary shopping lists, he said.</span></p>
<p class="p2 msg msg--info"><span class="s2"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Forest closures</span> </strong></span><span class="s1">The Big Hollow Fire was discovered Tuesday burning east and north of the Trapper Creek Wilderness on the Mount Adams Ranger District. Earlier Wednesday, the U.S. Forest Service had estimated the size of the fire to be 6,000 acres but later updated that number to about 22,000 acres. It reduced that estimate Thursday morning to 12,050 acres, in line with the estimate from the Department of Natural Resources.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p2 msg--highlight msg "><span class="s1">The cause of the fire is unknown.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">The<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong> Gifford Pinchot National Forest has temporarily closed</strong></span> some areas to the public, including developed campgrounds, dispersed camping, day use and wilderness areas, and most forest roads and trails in the southwestern portion of the forest, the U.S. Forest Service said in a news release Wednesday night.</span>
<blockquote><strong><span class="s1">“At this time, the Big Hollow Fire is presenting an extremely dangerous situation, and we must close the forest to protect the life and safety of the firefighters and the public,” Forest Supervisor Eric Veach said in the news release. “Even if your destination is outside the closure area, please consider waiting to visit the Gifford Pinchot or other national forests until the fire situation in the Northwest has stabilized somewhat.”</span></strong></blockquote>
</div>
</section>
<div class="article-inline advertisement my-6">
<div class="container-fluid text-center my-6">
<div id="instory-full-width-7"><hr></div>
</div>
</div>
<section class="article-content container px-lg-7">
<div class="mx-lg-7 px-lg-5 px-xl-7">
<p class="p1"><code><span class="s1">A forestwide ban on all campfires also went into effect Wednesday.</span></code></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Additional resources on wildfires can be found at: <a href="http://cresa911.org/wildfires-2020/">http://cresa911.org/wildfires-2020/</a>. Updates can be found at <a href="http://www.fs.usda.gov/alerts/giffordpinchot/alerts-notices">www.fs.usda.gov/alerts/giffordpinchot/alerts-notices</a> or call 360-524-1724.</span></p>
</div>
</section>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Do&#x27;s And Dont&#x27;s Of Face Masks - COVID 19 Chrisis Continues </title>
        <author>
            <name>Nolan Tanzman</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/the-dos-and-donts-of-face-masks-covid-19-chrisis-continues/"/>
        <id>https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/the-dos-and-donts-of-face-masks-covid-19-chrisis-continues/</id>
            <category term="COVID-19"/>

        <updated>2020-09-30T09:42:21-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    
  <p>
    <strong>Updated:<mark> <u>September 2020</u></mark></strong><mark></mark>
  </p>

    <h4 id="the-governors-statewide-requirement-that-all-employees-wear-face-coverings-in-their-workplace-goes-into-effect-june-8-this-seems-like-a-good-time-to-review-the-dos-and-donts-of-wearing-cloth-face-coverings">
      The Governor’s statewide requirement that all employees wear face coverings in their workplace goes into effect June 8. This seems like a good time to review the Do’s and Don’ts of wearing cloth face coverings.
    </h4>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    <strong>Updated:<mark> <u>September 2020</u></mark></strong><mark></mark>
  </p>

    <h4 id="the-governors-statewide-requirement-that-all-employees-wear-face-coverings-in-their-workplace-goes-into-effect-june-8-this-seems-like-a-good-time-to-review-the-dos-and-donts-of-wearing-cloth-face-coverings">
      The Governor’s statewide requirement that all employees wear face coverings in their workplace goes into effect June 8. This seems like a good time to review the Do’s and Don’ts of wearing cloth face coverings.
    </h4>
<hr id="read-more" />

  <p id="do-cover-your-face-with-a-couple-layers-of-cloth-while-in-public-placesbrbrdo-wash-your-hands-or-use-hand-sanitizer-before-you-put-your-mask-on-and-after-you-take-it-offbrbrdo-wash-your-cloth-face-covering-in-a-washing-machine-after-a-days-usebrbrdo-take-a-cloth-face-covering-with-you-if-you-are-hiking-or-visiting-a-park-although-you-do-not-need-to-wear-one-outside-you-may-find-that-you-need-to-come-within-6-feet-of-someone-else-on-a-trail-at-that-point-put-your-cloth-face-covering-on-say-hello-and-carry-onbrbrdo-make-sure-the-cloth-face-covering-covers-both-your-mouth-and-nose" class="msg msg--success align-center">
    (1.) DO cover your face with a couple layers of cloth while in public places.<br><br>(2.) DO wash your hands or use hand sanitizer before you put your mask on and after you take it off.<br><br>(3.) DO wash your cloth face covering in a washing machine after a day’s use.<br><br>(4.) DO take a cloth face covering with you if you are hiking or visiting a park. Although you do not need to wear one outside, you may find that you need to come within 6 feet of someone else on a trail. At that point, put your cloth face covering on, say hello, and carry on.<br><br>(6.) DO make sure the cloth face covering covers both your mouth and nose.
  </p>

  <p>
    <em><strong>Additional we have gathered some other useful information from trusted sources regarding what not to do with your mask.</strong></em>
  </p>

  <p class="msg msg--highlight align-center">
    (1.) DON’T wear surgical-grade masks or N95 respirators. We need to reserve those for health care and other frontline workers.<br><br>(2.) DON’T think that wearing cloth face masks means we can gather in large groups of people. For most of the state, all gatherings are prohibited. For the counties that are in Phase 2, all gatherings of more than 5 people outside your household are prohibited.<br><br>(3.) DON’T think that wearing a cloth face mask makes it safe to come within six feet of other people. At best, a cloth face covering is just one added level of precaution. It doesn’t really help unless we are also washing our hands, staying home when we are sick, and practicing physical distancing.<br><br>(4.) DON’T wear a cloth face covering while exercising outdoors. It’s not dangerous, just annoying and not necessary.<br><br>(5.) DON’T put a cloth face covering on a child under age 2 or on a person with a disability that keeps them from being able to remove it.<br><br>(6.) DON’T touch your cloth face covering after you put it on. Try not to touch your face at all.<br><br>(7.) DON’T worry that a cloth face covering might restrict your oxygen. It’s not airtight. If you ever feel like you’re having trouble breathing, remove the cloth face covering and sit down. If the feeling persists, call 911.
  </p>
<div> <a href='https://www.free-counters.org/'>Free-Counters.org</a> <publii-script type='text/javascript' src='https://www.freevisitorcounters.com/auth.php?id=d7ef7a13faee3eee4e5b53e440026e281e628bdc'></publii-script>
<publii-script type="text/javascript" src="https://www.freevisitorcounters.com/en/home/counter/744524/t/5"></publii-script></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>WA / OR Weather Advisory </title>
        <author>
            <name>Nolan Tanzman</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/wa-or-weather-advisory/"/>
        <id>https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/wa-or-weather-advisory/</id>
            <category term="Weather"/>
            <category term="Washington State"/>
            <category term="Oregon State"/>

        <updated>2020-09-30T09:42:21-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p class="msg msg--warning">...HIGH WIND WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 1 PM PDT TUESDAY...</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="msg msg--warning">...HIGH WIND WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 1 PM PDT TUESDAY...</p>

<div class="card-inner-wrapper">
<div class="card-content"><address class="align-center"><br><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>WHAT</strong></span>...East winds <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>15 to 30 mph</strong> </span>with widespread gusts of <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>40 to</strong></span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>55 mph are expected.</strong></span> Locally stronger winds with gusts of 60<br>to 65 mph are possible across the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>West Hills</strong> and areas east of</span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline;">the<strong> Portland Area Airport &amp; Vancouver Metro Area.</strong></span><br><hr><br><code>- <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">WHERE</span></strong>...Greater <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Portland</span> and <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Vancouver</span> metro area.</code><br><br><code><strong>- </strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>WHEN</strong></span>...Until 1 PM PDT Tuesday.</code><br><hr><br><code>- <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>IMPACTS</strong></span>..<span style="text-decoration: underline;">.Tree limbs and<strong> even whole trees</strong> will be susceptible</span></code><br><code><span style="text-decoration: underline;">to being blown down.</span> Be prepared for power outages.<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> Travel</span></code><br><code><span style="text-decoration: underline;">will be difficult,</span> especially for<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> high profile vehicles along</span></code><br><code><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Interstate 205.</span></strong></code><br><br><code><strong>- </strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ADDITIONALLY</strong></span>...Conditions will be favorable for rapid fire</code><br><code>spread. Use extreme caution with potential ignition sources.</code></address></div>
</div>
<div class="card-inner-wrapper inline-card-section">
<div class="card-content align-center">
<div class="align-center"><hr></div>
<pre id="instructions-section" class="inline-card"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><code>Recommended actions</code><br>People should avoid being outside in forested areas and around</strong></span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>trees and branches. If possible, remain in the lower levels of</strong></span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>your home during the windstorm, and avoid windows. Use caution if</strong></span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>you must drive.</strong></span></pre>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Washington State Health Department Update</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nolan Tanzman</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/washington-state-health-department-update/"/>
        <id>https://nolan-tanzman.github.io/washington-state-health-department-update/</id>
            <category term="Washington State"/>
            <category term="DOH"/>

        <updated>2020-09-30T09:42:21-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p class="msg msg--info"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Statement from the Department of Health</strong></span></p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="msg msg--info"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Statement from the Department of Health</strong></span></p>

<div class="post">
<p>The Washington State Department of Health is closely monitoring progress toward development of a vaccine for COVID-19. We are engaged in vaccine planning efforts and we will be ready to distribute a safe and effective vaccine as soon as the time comes. However, all vaccine candidates are still in clinical trials to determine their safety and efficacy.</p>
<p>DOH’s position is that any COVID-19 vaccine should complete Phase 3 trials before being distributed, unless an independent board of scientists reviewing the data finds otherwise based on data from those trials. At this crucial juncture, it is incumbent upon the federal government to critically evaluate these new vaccines for their safety and efficacy in an unbiased way.</p>
<p>In the meantime, DOH will continue working with federal and local partners to build the infrastructure needed for distribution. When a vaccine is ready, we will be prepared to deploy it in a manner ensure that is equitable, safe and timely for the people of Washington.</p>
</div>
<div class="related">
<h2> </h2>
</div>
<p class="align-center"><br><br></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
